RITA-LOUISE WAKEHNHI:IOSTHA FRIENDLY

ritafriendly.com linkedin.com/in/ritafriendly 603.715.7099 ritalouisefriendly@gmail.com

Proud Mohawk of the Iroquois Nation

UX Designer

ABOUT

I'm an organizational leader who loves to work collaboratively, beautify existing patterns and simplify experiences. I drive cohesive and intuitive experiences for my customers. I strive to learn about their behaviors, attitudes and emotions to help define experiences.

SKILLS

Sketch

Figma

Adobe XD

Adobe photoshop

Invision

Wireframing

Research

Prototyping

Affinity mapping

Design sprints

Project management

Remote work

EDUCATION

UX/UI Student

Flatiron School Seattle, WA June 2020

B.A. Biological Sciences,

Dartmouth College Hanover, NH 2013 Graduate

EXPERIENCE

BRATADAH - UX Designer

Contract: 4 Week Project

- Prototyped concept and wireframed 12 screens for final prototype providing the final eye editing for 20 screens to attain pixel perfect work screens
- Lead team discussions and maintained forward momentum during challenging design conversations through questions and time tracking
- Executed research plan conducting 12 interviews with customers and lead affinity mapping sessions to organize over 400 points of user data
- Conducted assumptive journey mapping workshop during client kickoff meeting and synthesized output into a beautiful journey map
- Driver of initial collaboration during ideation sessions with 3/5 of total ideas

YOGA BEHIND BARS - Corporate Development Specialist

March 2019-August 2019

- Spearheaded new program for community engagement with 8 studios across Seattle monthly workshops achieving highest donation of \$3k
- Social media strategy managing Facebook & Instagram presence with 4 new content posts a week increasing engagement by 8% and created documentation around social media standards and branding
- Managed yearly gala fundraiser raffle, volunteers and on-site management creatively theming baskets and raising over \$10k in raffle sales
- Created content for social media, website and printed assets for programs designing beautiful and mission focused materials

ARUP DESIGN & ENGINEERING - Project Administrator

Contract: July 2018-March 2019

- Managed engineering communications for WeWork, SeaTac and Washington State Convention Center projects smoothly facilitating companies workflows across 5 separate software systems
- Tracked project deadlines and maintained project documentation stepping in to organize 30 separate and disorganized WeWork projects to corresponding excel documents
- Crafted an immersive Alice in Wonderland holiday event experience for 80
- Assisted on RFP document researching Sound Transit projects providing organized excel project document

SPACE NEEDLE & CHIHULY GARDEN AND GLASS - Event Designer

July 2015-2017

- Partnered across two companies to execute a flawless end to end event experiences executing 250 events per year, clients include Boeing, Salesforce, Slalom Consulting, Microsoft, Amazon
- Managed multiple events simultaneously with varying deadlines 15% of events had less than 10 days to plan
- Managed processes for internal and external customers crafting solutions and recovered lost customer representing \$100k revenue annually
- Implemented rental delivery strategies within complex venue restrictions successfully delivered rentals from 4 vendors with only 1 elevator available for 2 separate 30 minute time slots without disturbing public guest experience